# KERU CHEN

Shijingshan District, Beijing, P.R. China

J +86 13901211166 

□ chenkeru0115@gmail.com 

□ zhihu.com/chenkeru

github.com/CLIVERCHEN

#### PERSONAL PROFILE

I am currently a junior majoring in Automation at Xi'an Jiaotong University. My research interests span the field of artificial intelligence, particularly reinforcement learning and its applications in areas like healthcare and robotics. I possess a strong sense of self-motivation, an aptitude for self-directed learning, and a knack for problem-solving. My fervent passion lies in scientific research.

# **EDUCATION**

### Xi'an Jiaotong University University

Bachelor of Engineering in Automation

# RELEVANT COURSEWOEK

- Data structures
- Operational research
- University Physics
- Computer graphic

- Programming design
- Machine learning
- Pattern recognition
- Reinforcement learning

#### EXPERIENCE

### Chinese Academy of Sciences

Feb 2023 - Oct 2023 Xi'an, China

Sep 2021 - Present

Current GPA: 3.6/4.3

Research intern

- Supervised by Prof. An Pan from Pioneering Interdiscipline Center, State Key Laboratory of Transient Optics and Photonics, CAS.
- I undertook the task of improving Fourier Ptychography Microscope algorithm and helped the professor complete the experiment.
- A review article titled Fourier ptychographic microscopy 10 years on: A review will be published soon on Cells (JCR Q1, IF=7.67).

# University of Houston & Washington State University

Aug 2023 – Present

Research intern

- Remote
- Supervised by Prof. Sen Lin and Prof. Honghao Wei from University of Houston and Washington State University respectively.
- Combining jump start reinforcement learning and constrained reinforcement learning, the algorithm is designed and analyzed theoretically.

# **PROJECTS**

# Face super-resolution based on deep learning

May 2022 - May 2023

- Participated in National Training Program of Innovation and Entrepreneurship for Undergraduates.
- Supervised by **Prof. Jingang Shi** from School of Software Engineering, Xi 'an Jiaotong University.
- We improved IDPT algorithm and build webdemo based on Flask and Ajax according to the algorithm to realize face detection, crop and super-resolution restoration of a given photo.

#### Four-wheeled robot with mechanical arms based on Mecanum wheel

Feb 2022 - Jun 2022

- Supervised by Prof. Jun Xu from State Key Laboratory for Manufacturing System Engineering, school of Mechanical Engineering, Xi'an Jiaotong University .
- Participated in the design of the robot arm structure, and completed the modeling and simulation with SolidWorks. Use Matlab and Simulink to complete the simulation of the manipulator control, and tune PID control.

#### Information propagation in social networks based on independent cascade model Apr 2023 – Jun 2023

- Supervised by Prof. Zhanbo Xu from Ministry of Education Key Lab For Intelligent Networks and Network Security, school of Automation Science and Engineering, Xi'an Jiaotong University.
- For a given network and the number of nodes that want to propagate, a more efficient propagation simulation algorithm is designed by combining Monte Carlo algorithm and heuristic algorithm.
- This project and its report have been uploaded to Github.

## Waveformer: A Transformer based EEG Sleep Stage Classifier

Oct 2023 - Nov 2023

- Supervised by Prof. Gang Wang from The Biomedical-Information Engineering laboratory of State Ministry of Education, school of Life Science and Technology, Xi'an Jiaotong University.
- Combined with transformer, wavelet transform and convolutional autoencoder, EEG is used to classify sleep stages, and the classification accuracy reaches 75%.
- This project and its report have been uploaded to Github.

 $\textbf{Technical Skills:} \ \ Python \ (PyTorch, \ Numpy, \ Pandas, \ etc.), \ C/C++, \ Matlab, \ \LaTeX, \ Git/GitHub, \ Linux, \ Altium \ Python \ (PyTorch, \ Numpy, \ Pandas, \ etc.), \ C/C++, \ Matlab, \ \LaTeX, \ Git/GitHub, \ Linux, \ Altium \ Python \ (PyTorch, \ Numpy, \ Pandas, \ etc.), \ C/C++, \ Matlab, \ \LaTeX, \ Git/GitHub, \ Linux, \ Altium \ Python \ (PyTorch, \ Numpy, \ Pandas, \ etc.), \ C/C++, \ Matlab, \ \LaTeX, \ Git/GitHub, \ Linux, \ Altium \ Python \ (PyTorch, \ Numpy, \ Pandas, \ etc.), \ C/C++, \ Matlab, \ \LaTeX, \ Git/GitHub, \ Linux, \ Altium \ Python \ (PyTorch, \ Numpy, \ Pandas, \ etc.), \ C/C++, \ Matlab, \ Matlab$ 

Designer, SolidWorks

Language: Mandarin (Native speaker) and English (Advanced)